我得说服你们做一件事
I have to talk all of you into doing something.
我知道我们必须这样做
Something I know we need to do.
我不知道该如何开口
And I don't know how to talk about it.
你想让我们做什么
What do you want us to do?
我想让你们活下去
I want you to survive.
我们在这里撑不了多久
We're not gonna last here.
行尸会成群结队地来袭
The biters, there'll be a herd of them.
它们会填满坑
They'll fill the pits,
一个叠一个
they'll crawl over one another.
前赴后继  最后入侵我们的营地
There'll be enough to tear right through our camp.
它们不来活人也会来
Or it'll be people.
我们和外面的世界之间没有阻碍
There's nothing between us and the rest of the world.
我们和他们之间毫无阻碍
Nothing between us and them.
我们留在这里  就会死
We stay here, we'll die.
摧毁了我和马丁内斯所在的营地的那些人
The people who destroyed the camp I was in with Martinez...
他们住在一座监狱里
they live in a prison.
在34号高速公路以北
It's north off Highway 34.
他们有围墙
They got walls...
栅栏
fences,
可供耕种的土地
plots of land for farming.
我们可以住在那里
We could live there.
如果我们愿意从他们手上抢过来的话
If we're willing to take it from 'em.
我有个计划  可以避免任何人受伤
I have a plan to do it without anyone getting hurt.
我抓获了他们的两个人
I captured two of them.
什么
What?
我当时在侦查监狱
I was scouting the prison
碰上了他们  所以我把他们带回来了
and our paths crossed, so I took 'em.
-你带回了他们  -他们是进监狱的钥匙
- You took them? - They're the key.
他们会帮我们不费一枪一弹夺取那座监狱
They're gonna help us take that prison without firing a shot.
我们能得到监狱  而且不必杀人
We can have it and we don't need to kill anyone.
但是
But...
我们得做好杀人的准备
we need to be prepared to.
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：冰蓝  重案组李sir  Reginamoon  小饭  送小孩  蘑菇
时间轴： 加森    雪贵人   后期： 、青衣
校对： 米小勒  冰蓝  送小孩     监制： 送小孩
监狱里的那些人并非都是坏人
The people in this prison, not all of them are bad.
但大部分都是小偷
But most of them are thieves,
谋杀犯
murderers.
为什么那种人能逍遥自在
Now why should people like that have peace of mind
而我们却每天都在掩埋同伴
when we're burying our own just about every day?
那些人致我残疾
These people, they mutilated me...
烧了我的营地
burned my camp...
杀了我女儿
killed my daughter.
你看见了  我尝试过
Now you saw me-- I tried.
我尝试过去死
I tried to die.
因为我不想接受  在这世界存活
'Cause I didn't want to accept that you couldn't live in this world
就必须杀人这一事实
without getting blood on your hands.
但我找到了你们  我不想死了
I found you people and I don't want to die.
我也不想让你们死
I don't want you to die.
我们得马上行动
Now we need to move-- now.
他们会发觉他们的人失踪了
They're gonna realize their people are gone
会为接下来的事做好准备
and they're gonna start getting ready for whatever's next.
我们得攻其不备  吓到他们
We need to surprise them. Scare them.
我们会赢的
And we will win.
我加入
I'm in.
-我加入  -我也是
- I'm in. - Me, too.
收拾东西  做好准备
Pack up and get ready.
半小时后我们定计划
We'll go over the plan in half an hour.
-走吧  -就这么做吧
- Come on. - Let's do it.
梅根在哪
Where's Megan?
她在拖车里看书
She's reading in the trailer.
你都听到了吗
You hear all that?
我说过我们不必抢另一个地方
I said we didn't have to fight for another place.
我知道
I know.
要杀人吗
Killing people?
不  杀谋杀犯
No. Killing killers.
你说过他们不全是坏人
You said they weren't all bad people.
他们和坏人在一起
Well, they're with bad people.
我也是吗
Am I?
我会让你活下去的
I'm gonna keep you alive.
我会让梅根活下去的
I'm gonna keep Megan alive.
我唯一在乎的
The only judgment on me I care about
就是你俩是不是活着
is whether you two are still breathing.
你听到了很好
It's good that you heard,
你知道了很好
that you know.
莉莉  我爱你
Lily... I love you.
我不知道你到底是谁
I don't know who you are.
你和我说过一定还有更好的地方
Hey, you told me there has to be someplace better
还叫我帮你找到它
and that I was gonna help you find it.
你了解我  莉莉
You knew me, Lily.
我是不会变的
It was always gonna be like this.
你也得收拾收拾了
You need to pack up, too.
-别碰我  -别动
- Don't touch me. - Stay still.
离我远点
Get off me.
你们应该吃点东西  今天将会是漫长的一天
You should eat. It's gonna be a long day.
没有人会伤害你们的
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
我可不信
I don't believe that.
我不在乎
Well, I don't care.
你就告诉我们这是怎么回事吧
Just tell us what this is.
拜托了
Please.
这不是私人恩怨
It isn't personal.
那这是什么
Then what is it?
米琼恩  我想让你明白
Michonne, I want you to know...
佩妮  我的女儿
Penny, my daughter,
她死了  我如今意识到了这一点
she was dead. I know that now.
现在  我不想伤害你
Now, I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤害任何人
I don't want to hurt anyone.
我只要监狱  就这么简单
I need the prison, that's it.
有一伙人的性命我得保住
There are people I need to keep alive.
你俩要帮我夺得监狱
You two are gonna help me take it.
不会有伤亡
No one needs to die.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
-我会用我的...  -别说了
- I'm gonna take my-- - Stop it.
度假好去处
你想要监狱
You want the prison?
是的  而且我会尽可能和平地接管它
Yeah. And I'll take it as peacefully as I can.
-总督  -别那样叫我
- Governor-- - Don't call me that.
你的人  还有我们的人
Your people, our people,
我们能找到一个和平共处的办法
we can find a way to live together.
这些你要护着的人
These people you need to keep alive,
你爱他们吗
do you love them?
你是个好人  赫谢尔
You're a good man, Hershel.
比瑞克要好
A better man than Rick.
你说的每一句话  你说话的方式
Everything you've said, the way you've said it,
证明你变了  而瑞克也变了
you've changed. So has Rick.
我们俩永远也不可能生活在一起的
The two of us will never be able to live together.
米琼恩和我  我们也不可能生活在一起
Michonne and I, we'll never be able to live together.
-我们会找到办法的  -我已经找到了
- We'll find a way. - I found a way!
我很努力了
I'm trying hard.
我有各种各样的办法能达到目的
There's all kinds of ways I could do this.
而这个办法  你们能活下去  而我能...
This way, you get to live and I get to be...
你说你想尽可能和平地接管这个监狱
You say you want to take this prison as peacefully as possible.
那意味着为了夺得它你也不惜伤害一些人
That means you'd be willing to hurt people to get it.
我的女儿们在那儿
My daughters would be there.
你有可能伤害到她们
That's who you'd be hurting.
假如你真理解有个女儿的感觉
If you understand what it's like to have a daughter,
那你怎么能威胁别人女儿的性命
then how can you threaten to kill someone else's?
因为她们不是我的女儿
Because they aren't mine.
我们回来前他们会安全地待在这儿
They'll be safe here until we get back.
行尸没办法过河
Biters can't make it across the water.
假如在水边很安全的话
If it's safe by the water,
那我们就直接找个靠水的地方啊
then let's just go someplace by the water.
-莉莉  -你没必要这么做
- Lily. - You don't have to do this.
任何安全的地方  真正安全的地方
Anyplace that's safe, really safe,
都已经被人占了
someone's already there.
为梅根想想  好吗
Think about Megan, huh?
我想过
I am.
她在这样的一个世界上会变成什么样
What's she gonna be in this world?
她会成为幸存者
She's gonna be alive.
在做泥巴馅饼呢
Making mud pies?
花生酱三明治
Peanut butter sandwiches.
在我走之前抱抱我怎样
How about a hug before I go?
我手上都是泥巴
My hands are muddy. See?
的确
Oh, yeah.
好吧  我可不想把我的外套弄脏
Well, I wouldn't want to get my coat dirty.
我把你弄得一团糟
I messed it all up.
没有  你让我更好了
No, you made it better.
我真想度个假
I could use a vacation.
出去散散心
Get away.
一个周末就好
Just for a weekend.
是啊
Yeah.
我们的周年纪念日快到了
You know, our anniversary is coming up.
是吗
It is?
就这几天
One of these days.
你去过阿米科罗拉瀑布吗
You ever been to Amicalola Falls?
乔治亚最高的瀑布
Tallest waterfall in Georgia.
小时候我爸爸带我去过
My dad took me there when I was little.
我们站在顶端的时候
When we were up there,
从上往下看
all the way at the top looking down,
我感觉像是在飞一样
I felt like I was flying.
我现在就去给旅行车装行李
I'll go load up the station wagon.
我去给你拿点水喝
I'm gonna get you some water.
-我能去拿  -我知道
- I can get it. - I know.
但是我要去
But I'm doing it.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你就不能等我们回来再处理这事吗
Man, you couldn't have waited till we got back?
等泰尔西回来吗
Until Tyreese got back?
我能应付他
I could've handled that.
她杀了两个自己人
She killed two of our own.
她不能待在这里
She couldn't be here.
她会没事的
She's gonna be all right.
她有一辆车  供给品还有武器
She has a car, supplies, weapons.
她...她能活下去
She's a survivor.
这话连你自己都不相信
Stop saying that like you don't believe it.
她杀了人  她说是为了我们大家
She did it. She said it was for us.
她就是那么想的
That's how it was in her head.
她不觉得愧疚
She wasn't sorry.
她是这样  但这不是她的本性
Man, that's her, but that ain't her.
那两个小女孩怎么办
What are we supposed to do about those two girls?
我告诉她我们会照顾她们
I told her we'd look after them.
我还没有告诉泰尔西
I haven't told Tyreese yet.
我不知道他会有什么反应
I don't know how he's gonna take it.
我们去看看就得了
Let's go find out.
鲍勃
Bob.
你应该休息
You should be resting.
折腾了一晚上  你也应该休息了
After the night you had, so should you.
我要休息
I'm going to.
我正要去C区找一个空狱房
On my way to find an open cell in C block
直到D区被收拾干净了
until D gets cleaned up.
我只想说
I just wanted to say
谢谢
thank you.
如果不是赫谢尔跟你的话
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for Hershel
我不会活着
and you.
多亏了赫谢尔  不是我
Hershel, not me.
-你也帮忙了  -别说了
- You helped save my life. - Stop.
-鲍勃  -别说了
- Bob. - Stop.
你把那些药放到了我的输液里
You put those meds in my IV bag.
现在  还有几分钟
And now, in a couple minutes,
我就能看到明天的太阳了
I'm gonna feel the sun on my skin.
所以你得让我谢谢你
So you are gonna let me thank you.
萨沙
Sasha.
你还没有完全恢复
You're not strong enough yet.
那就帮帮我
Then help me.
泰尔西  你在吗
Tyreese. You down here?
瑞克  是你吗
Rick, that you?
你们得来看看
You guys got to see this.
能一会儿再去吗  我们得先谈谈
Can we take a beat? There's something we need to talk about.
那个不着急  先过来
It can wait. Come on.
看
Look.
怎么回事
The hell?
我刚才在找
I was just looking for...
答案
answers...
然后我发现了这个
and I found this.
是杀掉凯伦和大卫的人干的
Same person that killed Karen and David did this.
还记得栅栏那里的老鼠吗
Remember the rats at the fence?
它们是在她被杀当天出现的
They showed up the same day she was killed.
我们队伍里有个变态
We got a psychopath living with us.
-泰尔西  -我们得找到他  瑞克
- Tyreese. - We got to find him, Rick.
不找到他我决不罢休
And I'm not gonna sleep until we do.
泰尔西
Tyreese...
干这事的
whoever did this,
恐怕不是杀死凯伦的凶手
I don't think that's who killed Karen.
为什么
Why?
快走
Come on.
退后
Get back!
瑞克
Rick!
过来吧
Come down here.
我们谈谈
We need to talk.
我做不了主
It's not up to me.
我们有委员会  由他们管理这里
There's a council now. They run this place.
委员会里有赫谢尔吗
Is Hershel on the council?
还有米琼恩呢
What about Michonne?
委员会也有她吗
She on the council, too?
这里不再由我做决定了
I don't make decisions anymore.
今天你得做  瑞克
You're making the decisions today, Rick.
过来  我们谈谈吧
Come down here. Let's have that talk.
我们能行  好吗
We can do this. All right?
我们对付不了这么多人
We can't take 'em all on.
咱们按照之前计划的
We'll go through the admin building,
穿过管理楼进入林子
through the woods like we planned.
我们现在没有人数优势了
We ain't got the numbers no more.
上次查大巴上的补给是什么时候
When's the last time someone checked the stash on the bus?
我们去基地的前一天
Day before we hit the Big Spot.
那时我们的口粮不多  现在更少了
We were running low on rations then. We're lower now.
我们会想到办法的  如果情况不妙
Yeah, we'll manage. Things go south,
通知大家  都上大巴
everyone heads for that bus. Let everybody know.
如果情况不妙却没人知道呢
What if everybody doesn't know when things go bad?
我们要等多久
How long do we wait?
尽可能多等一会儿
As long as we can.
现在就放他们走
Let 'em go right now.
我留下
I'll stay down here.
你想谈多久就谈多久
Talk as long as you want.
但你得放他们走
But you let 'em go.
你有坦克  完全不需要人质
You got a tank. You don't need hostages.
我需要
I do.
这是为了告诉你我是认真的
This is just to show you I'm serious.
我才不会给新家轰个大洞呢
Not to blast a hole in our new home.
你和你的人  日落之前离开这里
You and your people, you have till sundown to get out of here
否则他们就得死
or they die.
没必要这样吧
Doesn't have to go down this way.
我的人马和武器都比你多
I got more people, more firepower.
我们需要这座监狱
We need this prison.
就是这样
There it is.
跟以前无关  一切只关乎现在
It's not about the past. It's about right now.
这里有孩子
There are children here.
有的病了  在外面他们活不下去
Some of them are sick. They won't survive.
我有辆坦克
I have a tank.
却让你们安全地离开这里
And I'm letting you walk away from here.
还有什么好废话的
What else is there to talk about?
你还好吗
You good?
还好
Yeah.
拿着
All right.
妈妈
Mommy,
你能帮我挖吗
can you please help me dig?
妈妈  能帮我吗
Mommy, can you please help me?
我马上过去  亲爱的
I'll be right there, honey.
妈妈  太沉了
Mommy, it's too heavy.
我听到了
I hear you.
我马上过去
I'll be there in a sec.
很抱歉  亲爱的  你刚说什么
I'm sorry, honey. What did you say?
没关系  我自己能行
It's okay. I can do it myself.
警告
山洪多发地段
梅根
Megan!
妈妈  妈妈
Mommy! Mommy!
妈妈
Mommy!
梅根
Megan!
我可以向你们开火
I could shoot you all.
你们会反击  我知道
You'd all shoot back. I know that.
但最终我们会赢  你们会死的
But we'll win and you'll be dead.
全都会死
All of you.
没必要那样
Doesn't have to be like that.
如我先前说的  由你选择
Like I said, it's your choice.
动静太大只会吸引更多行尸
Noise will only draw more of them over.
你等得越久
The longer you wait,
你们就越难以离开这里
the harder it will be for you to get out of here.
我们得做点什么
We got to do something.
你爸爸能处理
Your dad's got it.
他们只顾着说话
They're talking.
我们现在就可以杀了总督
We could kill the Governor right now.
-隔着45米远吗  -我枪法很好
- From 50 yards? - I'm a good shot.
我现在就可以结束这一切
I could end this right now.
是啊  或者失手了挑起战斗
Yeah, or you could start something else.
你要信任他
You got to trust him.
你们要去哪
Where are you guys going?
-去大巴上  走吧  -不行
- To the bus. Come on. - No.
这是计划  我们应该去大巴上
You know the plan. That's where we're supposed to go.
卡萝尔告诉我们要坚强
Carol told us to be strong.
保护自己  他们有枪
To protect ourselves. They have guns.
我们也应该有枪
We should have guns, too.
我们应该去帮忙
We should help.
太阳下山前  你们大概还有一个小时
You got maybe about an hour of sunlight left.
我建议你们开始打包
I suggest you start packing.
拖得时间越久
The longer you wait,
越难从这里安全离开
the harder it's gonna be for you to get out of here.
我们可以
We can all--
我们可以一块住
we can all live together.
房间足够全部人住进去了
There's enough room for all of us.
地方是很充裕
More than enough.
但我的家人跟你们住在同一屋檐下
But I don't think my family would sleep well knowing
是睡不了安稳觉的
that you were under the same roof.
我们可以住在不同的牢房区
We'd live in different cell blocks.
在我们能接受对方之前
We'd never have to see each other
我们不用见面
till we're all ready.
这方法可行
It could work.
你知道的
You know it could.
是有可能
It could've.
但是不能这样
But it can't.
经历了伍德伯里
Not after Woodbury.
和安德莉亚的事情之后  不能这样
Not after Andrea.
我并没有说  这可以轻松实现
Look, I'm not saying it's gonna be easy.
事实上  这比我们站在这里互相开枪
Fact is, it's gonna be a hell of a lot harder
要难上一万倍
than standing here shooting at each other.
但我们没有其它选择
But I don't think we have a choice.
我们没有  你们有
We don't. You do.
我们不会离开的
We're not leaving.
如果你想逼我们离开  我们会拼死抵抗
You try and force us, we'll fight back.
就像你刚才说过的
Like you said,
枪声会引来更多行尸
the gunshots will just bring more of them out.
它们会挤倒围栏
They'll take down the fences.
没有了围栏  这个地方就毫无价值了
Without the fences, this place is worthless.
我们要不然就一起住在监狱
Now, we can all live in the prison
要不然就谁都住不了
or none of us can.
我们会修好那个该死的围栏的
We'll fix the damn fences.
不要
No--!
你  梳马尾辫的那个姑娘
You. You in the ponytails.
这是你想要的吗  这是你们想要的吗
Is this what you want? Is this what any of you want?
我们想要的就是你们的监狱
What we want is what you got.
就是这样
Period.
你们该滚蛋了  混蛋
Time for you to leave, asshole.
听着  我以前和他打过
Look, I fought him before.
之后  我们收留了他以前的同伴
And after, we took in his old friends.
他们成了我们这里的领导者
They've become leaders in what we have here.
如果你们现在放下武器
Now you put down your weapons,
从那些门进来
walk through those gates...
你们就是我们的一员
you're one of us.
我们既往不咎
We let go of all of it,
没人会伤亡
and nobody dies.
所有现在活着的人
Everyone who's alive right now.
所有坚持到现在的人
Everyone who's made it this far.
为了活下去  我们都不择手段过
We've all done the worst kinds of things just to stay alive.
但是我们依旧可以回头
But we can still come back.
我们还没有走得太远
We're not too far gone.
我们还可以回头
We get to come back.
我知道
I know...
我们都是可以改变的
we all can change.
骗子
Liar.
不要
No!
爸
Dad!
爸爸
Daddy!
你
You!
举起枪  快战斗
Pick up your weapon! Fight, now!
这不对
This isn't right.
-我们不该这样做  -必须这么做
- We're not supposed to be doing this. - We are.
他竟然用刀砍下了那人的头
He chopped a guy's head off with a sword.
我们必须留下  已经太晚了
We have to stay here. It's too late.
你明白吗
You understand me?
跟在我后面  如果我们走散了
Stay behind me and if we get separated,
你就找一个安全的地方躲起来
you just go run somewhere safe and hide.
听见了吗  找个安全的地方躲起来
You hear me? You go someplace safe and hide
等这一切结束后  我会去找你
and I will find you when this is all over. I will find you.
开车进围栏
Go through the fence in your cars.
拿上枪  我们进去
Get your guns, we go in.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
遵命  前进
Roger that. Move in!
前进
Go ahead!
我没弹药了
I'm out of ammo.
跑去大巴那边  我掩护你
Run for the bus. I'll cover you.
上去
Move up!
快跑  离开这里
Go! Get out of here!
快跑  格伦还在里面  我得去接他
Go, go! Come on! Glenn's in there. I have to get him.
-我跟你一起  -不  你去让人们上大巴
- I'm going with you. - No, get these people on the bus.
-随时准备出发  我马上回来  -如果你回不来呢
- Be ready to drive. I'll be right back. - What if you're not?
-那就丢下我先走  -我不能丢下你
- You have to go without us. - I won't go without you.
贝丝  让大家上大巴  好吗
Beth, get these people on the bus, okay?
这是你的职责  我们要各司其职
It's your job. We've all got jobs to do.
-格伦  -发生了什么
- Glenn! - What the hell's going on?
我们得带大家离开这里
We have to get everybody out of here.
贝丝  贝丝在哪
Beth! Where's Beth?
-她去找你了  -她去了哪里
- She went to find you. - Where?
我们会找到她的  她会没事的
We'll find her. She'll be okay.
-别来  -什么  不行  你不能自己去
- No. - What? No, you're not going by yourself.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
玛姬
Maggie...
右边
On your right.
手榴弹
Grenade!
萨沙  萨沙  你看见贝丝了吗
Sasha! Sasha! Have you seen Beth?
-她在大巴上吗  -没有  她...
- Is she on the bus? - No. She's--
别起身
We gotta stay down.
掀开衣服  看看子弹有没有穿过
Look inside my shirt. Check my back for an exit wound.
穿过了
Yeah.
太好了  还能治疗
That's good. We can treat it.
-不能在这里治  -低头  我们找个安全的地方
- Not here. - Stay down. We'll find someplace safe.
我们想别的办法  快走
We'll figure it out. Come on.
我们必须离开这里
We got to get out of here.
等等  去那边
Hey! We go that way!
卡尔
Carl...?
卡尔在哪
Where's Carl?
我不知道
I don't know.
手榴弹
Grenade!
我在找孩子们  让他们上大巴
I was trying to find the kids to get them on the bus.
我们必须走了  贝丝  必须走了
We got to go, Beth. We got to go.
卡尔
Carl!
Carl?
朱迪思
Judith.
她在哪里
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know.
不
No.
卡尔  卡尔
Carl. Carl.
我们必须离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
我们必须走了
We've got to go.
结束了
It's over.
别回头  卡尔
Don't look back, Carl.
一直走下去
Just keep walking.